That weapon has the power to destroy
the balance of the world
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)あの兵器は
世界のバランスを崩し➡
and lead it down the path
of its own destruction.
崩壊へと導く力です｡➡
バハムートのように！
Just as Bahamut!
Hug me.
(ﾆｰﾅ･ﾄﾞﾗﾝｺﾞ)ギュッとして｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)私は 神の国に行きたい｡
I would like to go to the land of the gods.
Yeah, the old lady back in my village
would talk about it all the time.
うん｡ 確か 里のばあちゃんが
昔 よく行ってたって｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)行こう ニーナの里へ｡
Then let us go to your village.
≪(隊長)報告に参りました｡
Your Highness.
We have not yet ascertained the whereabouts
(隊長)脱獄したジャンヌ･ダルク➡
of the fugitives Jeanne D'Arc,
Favaro Leone and Nina Drango.
ファバロ･レオーネ
ニーナ･ドランゴの行方は➡
いまだ つかめておりません｡➡
There have been multiple eyewitness accounts.
It is the same regarding the mysterious child.
多数 目撃情報のあった
謎の子供に関しても同様です｡➡
カイザル･リドファルドを
拷問にかけておりますが➡
We are interrogating Kaisar Lidfard harshly,
but he has maintained his silence.
何も吐きません｡
As expected of the Orleans Knight captain.
(ｼｬﾘｵｽ17世)さすがは
オルレアン騎士団の団長だな｡
ひっ！
もう少し➡
I see you were not ready for your job.
腕を上げてから来い｡
脱獄犯は お前たちに任せる｡
-I will leave the fugitives to you.
-Yes, My Lord.
余は エイボスに向かう｡
I will be heading to Eibos.
Rage of Bahamut
They are the same
And lose themselves
Cuz there are lots of roads to go
But I realize it's the road that's getting rougher
I wanna walk straight ahead
I lose another dream
Most are broken before they can come true
But walk this way
Get out of my way
Depends on the way you think it
What the yielding heart reflects
Future, hope
Despair, insecurity It's all the same
As hard as I kick
The reality which is lying
To the person I was when I prepared for it all
Go your way don't you?
But walk this way
Get out of my way
But Walk this way
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)うっ！
カチャ(鍵を掛ける音)
≫コツ コツ…
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)あぁ…｡
Get up! You have a visitor.
≫(兵士)面会だ 起きろ｡
Dias!
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)ディアス｡➡
It seems that I'm a real jailbird now.
牢獄生活が
すっかり 板に付いてしまった｡
(ﾃﾞｨｱｽ)鉄格子を握るより
あなたには剣が似合いますよ｡
An iron sword would suit you more than these iron bars.
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)騎士団はどうだ？
How are the knights?
I suppose not much can be expected
when their captain is imprisoned.
団長が捕まっていては
どうもこうもないか｡
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)ディアス➡
Dias, I leave the Orleans Knights in your hands.
オルレアン騎士団を頼む｡
(ﾃﾞｨｱｽ)あっ… 団長は あなたです｡
You are the captain!
I met Jeanne.
ジャンヌ様に会った｡
(ﾃﾞｨｱｽ)はっ… ジャンヌ様に？
Jeanne?
あの方は
何も変わってはいなかった｡
She hadn't changed.
The Orleans Knights will rise again.
オルレアン騎士団は必ず復活する｡
ジャンヌ様と共に
よみがえらせるのだ｡
Jeanne is our salvation.
分かりました｡
ジャンヌ様と私と➡
Yes. The three of us will return the knights to glory.
あなたとで｡
I see it! My house is right over there!
あそこ あそこ！
私の家は あそこだよ｡
お～い！ はははっ はははっ｡
Hey!
ははっ 痛いって｡
I'm home!
たっだいま～！
(一同)ん？
ひひひひっ｡
(子供たち)ニーナ！
-Nina!
Ow! Hey, you mean Sis, not Nina!
｢ニーナ｣じゃないでしょ｡
(子供たち)ニーナ！
-Nina! How have you been?
-Nina's back!
ニーナ｡
おばちゃん！ ニーナ 帰って来たよ｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)あっ｡
ニャー
あっ ピヨピヨだ！
Hey, it's Peep-Peep! This is a mora-
it's name's Peep-Peep!
この子 モーラのピヨピヨだよ｡
ニャー ニャー ニャー
Why Peep-Peep?
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)なぜ ｢ピヨピヨ｣なのだ？
えっ？
I don't know. But it's cute, isn't it?
分かんない｡
けど かわいいでしょ？
Is that you, Nina!
(母)おかえりなさい ニーナ｡
-I'm home!
-I'm so glad you're home.
ただいま～｡
(母)いらっしゃい｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)あっ 私は…｡
私の友達のジャンヌさんだよ｡
I am...
This is my friend, Jeanne.
So that's what they're wearing
in the capital nowadays.
(母)王都では
そういう服が はやっているのね｡
おかえり ニーナ！
ただいま～！
Welcome back, Nina!
Thanks!
(女性)おかえり ニーナ｡
ただいま！
Welcome home, Nina!
Thanks!
≫(女性)おかえり ニーナ｡
ただいま～！
-Welcome back, Nina!
-Thanks!
ニーナ おかえり｡
たっだいま～！
Nina, welcome back!
Thanks!
Jeanne, hurry up!
ジャンヌさん 早く～！
置いていきますよ～！
I'm going to leave you behind!
バシャン！(泉に飛び込む音)
バシャン！
I'm back, Granny!
ただいま～ ばあちゃん！
里のばあちゃんです｡
This is our village elder.
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
I am Jeanne D'Arc.
ジャンヌ… ダルクです｡
She's not a statue.
置物じゃないよ｡
うっ…｡
Nina! You've gotten thin.
(族長)
ニーナ おめ 細くなったな｡➡
What happened?
なじょした？
なんだかんだっす｡
You know, this and that.
それよか ばあちゃん
友達のジャンヌさんが➡
Anyway, Granny,
my friend Jeanne is begging
to get to the land of the gods.
なじょしても
神の国さ行きてぇって言ってんだ｡
Now, I know you've been there before, Granny.
ばあちゃん
神の国さ行ったことあんべ？
Could you tell us how you got there?
行き方 教えてくんりょ｡
Please, Granny!
お願い ばあちゃん｡
飲むか？ ん？
(２人)いや… どうぞ｡
Wanna sip?
-No, thank you.
Two thousand years ago,
the gods and demons worked together
2000年前
神と悪魔は 力合わして➡
to take down Bahamut.
バハムートをやっつけたっきょ｡➡
And so I took the tired gods
そんとき
力尽きた神々を背中に乗っけて➡
and carried them to their homeland on my back.
神の国まで連れて帰ってやったんは
わしなんじゃ｡
でた！ また その話だぎゃ｡
Yeah! I love this story!
あれを見ろ｡
(２人)ん？
Look at that.
(族長)あれは
あんときの わしの雄姿だべ｡➡
That's what I looked like back then.
どや？ かっこいいやろ｡
ほれぼれするど？
Pretty cool, right? I was a looker!
ばあちゃん 大丈夫か？
Granny, are you all right?
There' s no way you could fit
everyone on your little back.
この背中に乗れるわけねぇべ｡
-Pshaw!
-Oh, she's mad!
もう知らね｡
あっ 怒った｡
Hey, Nina!
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)おい ニーナ｡
ん？
どうしても
神の国へ行きたいのです｡➡
I must go to the land of the gods.
I implore your help.
何とぞ ご協力を｡
Sorry, Granny!
ごめん ばあちゃん｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)何とぞ｡
I implore you!
ばあちゃん｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)何とぞ｡
-Granny!
-I implore you!
ばあちゃん？
(族長)ぐぅ～…➡
Granny?
寝ちゃった｡
あっ…｡
She fell asleep.
ばあちゃん
寝たら起きないから➡
You can't wake her up once she falls asleep.
明日 また来よ？
Let's just come back tomorrow.
うい～ ふぅ～｡
This is wonderful.
これは すばらしいな｡
このお湯 すごいんだよ｡
ケガも治るし 疲れも取れるの｡
The water's amazing.
It even has healing powers.
ねえねえ ジャンヌさん➡
Hey, Jeanne, is Mugaro's dad cool?
ムガロちゃんのお父さんって
かっこいいの？
I mean, he has to be.
You've got it down, Jeanne.
いいよね そりゃあ｡
やるなぁ ジャンヌさん｡
あの方は
そういうものではないんだ｡
I did not view that gentleman in such a way.
｢あの方｣だって｡
うふふっ｡ エッチ！
That gentleman? You're so dirty!
恋とか 愛とか
そういったものとは違う｡
What was between us was not romantic.
What? But they say that children are the fruit of love.
ええ～？
でも 子供は 愛の結晶でしょ？
あの方は 今も エルと私を
見守ってくださっている｡
I know he is still watching over El and me.
それが全てだ｡
ん？
That is everything.
そなたは どうなのだ？
えっ 私？
What about you?
What? Me?
慕っている男性は いないのか？
Has a man captured your heart?
Yes.
いる…｡
私 かっこいい男の人に近づくと
竜になって暴れちゃうから➡
Since I transform into a dragon
when I get near a handsome man,
I've never really been able
to get close to anyone like that.
ずっと そういう人と
仲よくできなかったんだ｡
But he's the only one I've been able to dance with.
でも その人だけは
一緒に踊ることができたの｡
I felt safe when I was with him.
一緒にいて すごく安心できて
幸せな気持ちだった｡
I was really happy.
私が生まれてきたのは➡
It almost felt like I was born to dance with him.
この人と踊るためだったんだって
思えるくらい｡
Is this your first love?
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)初恋なのか？
Yeah. Maybe.
そうね… そうかもね｡
That is wonderful.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)それは すてきだな｡
ジャンヌさんの初恋は
どんなだったの？
What was your first love like?
I don't know.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)私は… 分からないんだ｡➡
I received my divine revelation before I knew romance
恋を知る前に啓示を受け
神のしもべとして戦場にいた｡
and charged into battle as a servant of the gods.
Are the gods' servants not allowed to love?
神のしもべって 恋できないの？
I hope you will find happiness with that person.
ニーナは
その者と幸せになれるといいな｡
でもね 私の好きな人➡
Well, the thing is, the person I fell for
私の大嫌いな人だったの｡
turned out to be someone I hated.
So I have no idea what I should do.
だから
どうしていいか分からなくて｡
すごくいい人なのに➡
He's really a great guy,
but he's done a lot of horrible things.
恐ろしいこと いっぱいしてて｡
But you still like him?
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)それでも好きなのか？
分からない｡
I don't know.
それでも嫌いになれない｡
I still can't bring myself to hate him.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)私の中にも
いろいろな顔の自分がいる｡
I too have many different faces.
あっ｡
ニーナの好きな人が➡
It is not strange that the man you like
would have contradictions.
相反する顔を持っていたとしても
不思議はない｡
Really?
そうなの？
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)もし ニーナが➡
If you are able to embrace
those contradictions too,
その者の
全ての顔を愛せるのなら➡
then your love may be real.
その恋は 本物かもしれない｡
(子供たち)フゥ～！
(子供)わ～い！
(子供たち)ぷはっ！
(子供たち)ははっ｡
こら！ あんたたち！
Hey, you guys!
Dinnertime!
(母)ご飯よ！
(子供たち)は～い！
Coming!
わあ～！
ジャンヌさん 似合う～！
そうか？
Jeanne, that looks so good on you!
Really?
Looking real good!
(一同)イケてる イケてる！➡
Time to eat!
いっただきま～す！
How long can you stay, Nina?
(母)
ニーナは いつまでいられるの？
We'll be taking a trip to the land of the gods tomorrow.
明日 ちょっと
神の国に行ってくる｡
-Land of the gods? I'll go too!
-Me too!
(子供)神の国？ 俺も行く！
(子供)俺も！
ダメ｡ 簡単には行けないんだから｡
You can't come! It's not that simple.
神の国に何しに行くの？
Why are you going to the land of the gods?
-To go see Mugaro.
-Mugaro?
ムガロちゃんに会いに行く｡
ムガロちゃん？
(子供たち)誰？ それ｡
Who's that?
ムガロちゃんは
ジャンヌさんの子供で➡
Mugaro is Jeanne's holy child,
and he's been separated from her.
生き別れの聖なる子だよ｡
(子供)聖なる子？ 分かんない｡
(子供)うん 俺は分かる｡
Holy child?
I don't get it.
-I get it though.
-Liar.
(子供)うそつけ！
(子供)分かるもん！
-I'm not lying!
-Then who is it?
(子供)じゃあ 誰だよ？
(子供)聖なる子は 聖なる子だよ！
-The holy child is the holy child!
-So who is that holy child, then?
(子供)
だから 聖なる子って誰だよ？
眠れないの？➡
Can't sleep?
There's water over there.
水なら そこに｡
すみません｡
Thank you.
We can talk if you'd like.
よかったら 少し お話ししましょ｡
Thank you.
はい｡
It's a strange village, isn't it?
(母)不思議な里でしょう ここは｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)ええ｡
Yes.
私も最初は 衝撃的だったわ｡
I was really overwhelmed at first too.
あっ 私は 竜族じゃないの｡
Oh, I'm not dragonfolk.
I'm from a nearby village, and I married in.
麓の村の出身で 嫁いできたのよ｡
Nina is a wonderful child.
ニーナは とてもいい子ですね｡
ありがと｡
Thank you.
Those are pictures of the parents
of the children we take care of.
(母)あれね
うちで預かってる子たちの➡
ご両親の絵よ｡➡
The village is poor,
so they are all out earning money for everyone.
この里も景気が悪くってねぇ…➡
みんなで出稼ぎに行ってるの｡
Even Nina's father?
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)ニーナのお父さんも？
Her father died.
あの子の父親は 死んだわ｡
He wanted to protect the village
from the fireball 10 years ago.
１０年前 あの火の玉から
里を守ろうとして 逃げ遅れて…｡
Did Nina cause any trouble for you
turning into a dragon or anything?
(母)あの子 突然 竜になって
迷惑かけなかった？
No, she saved my life.
いえ 命を助けてもらいました｡
Really? She's growing up, isn't she?
へえ～｡
あの子も成長したのかしら｡
Ever since her father died,
whenever she gets near a man like him,
あの子 お父さんが死んだ日から➡
お父さんくらいの男の人に
近づくと➡
竜になって
暴れるようになっちゃったの｡➡
she'll turn into a dragon and go on a bit of a rampage.
つらい記憶を思い出すのを
拒否するようにね｡
Almost as if to avoid painful memories.
(母)ありがと ジャンヌさん｡➡
Thank you, Jeanne.
あの子と友達になってくれて
ありがと｡
Thank you for being her friend.
やめてください｡
Please don't. I am not a person
who deserves to be thanked.
私は 感謝されていい人間では
ありません｡
I am... I am the one who...
私は…｡
私がニーナの…｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)はっ｡
大変だったね｡
It must have been hard.
I can tell from how attached she is.
あの子の懐き具合で分かるわ➡
あなたが
ニーナに優しくしてくれたこと｡
I can tell how kind you've been to her.
だから ありがと｡
So thank you.
(母)つらかったね｡
You've been through so much.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)ううぅ～！➡
ううぅ～…｡
(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ)ぶえぇ～！
(ｹﾙﾍﾞﾛｽ)｢あららら…｣｡
(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ)ごほっ ごほっ…｡
(ｹﾙﾍﾞﾛｽ)だから➡
See? I told you to stop.
もうやめなって言ったのに～｡
(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ)ごほっ ごほっ ごほっ｡➡
ケル子 こ… こんなときは
あれを言ってくれ｡
Cerby, I need you to say it again for me.
(ｹﾙﾍﾞﾛｽ)ええ～？
(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ)早く言え！
-What?
-Do it!
(ｹﾙﾍﾞﾛｽ)あんたが団長…｡
(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ)もっと大きく！
You're the captain now.
-Louder!
-You're the captain now!
(ｹﾙﾍﾞﾛｽ)あんたが団長！
(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ)よ～し➡
お前を 団長の嫁にしてやるぞ！
(ｹﾙﾍﾞﾛｽ)ええ～？
I'll make you the captain's wife!
What?
Get it together, Captain.
(ｹﾙﾍﾞﾛｽ)しっかりしろよ 団長｡
(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ)ごほっ…｡
≫(ﾃﾞｨｱｽ)やはり ここだったか｡
(ｹﾙﾍﾞﾛｽ)ん？
I thought you'd be here.
(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ)
ううっ はぁ…｡ おっ 副団長！➡
Oh, hey there, Vice Captain!
ちわ～っす！ はははっ｡
(ｹﾙﾍﾞﾛｽ)あっ…｡
お前は
オルレアン騎士団の騎士だ！
You are an Orleans Knight!
What's the big idea?
じょ… 冗談じゃないですか｡
何 本気で怒ってんすか？➡
What are you getting mad for?
ちょっと ケ… ケル子～！
(ｹﾙﾍﾞﾛｽ)まいど｡ ｢バイバ～イ｣｡
-Cerby!
-Please come back soon!
Did you get enough sleep? I sure did.
(族長)
お前たち よく寝れたべか？➡
わしは よく寝た｡
でしょうね｡
I bet.
(族長)
お前たち 本気で行く気だべか？
Are you two serious about going?
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)お願いします｡
お願いします｡
-Yes.
うむ…｡ うん｡
イエ～ス！
ふぅ…｡
Yes!
で どうやって行くの？
So how do we get there?
だから わしの背中に
乗せてやると言ったべさ｡
I told you! I'll carry you on my back.
ええ～？ だって その背中…｡
What? But your back won't-
≫ドドォーン！
うわ～！
ごほっ ごほっ ごほっ…｡
Mom, I'm off, then!
お母さん 行ってくるね！
ああ 行ってらっしゃい｡
≪(子供)ニーナ➡
Have a safe trip!
Nina.
おみやべ 待ってる｡
天使 連れて 帰って来る｡
Bring back souvenirs.
I'll bring home an angel.
(子供たち)わあ～！
(子供)やった～！
(子供)やったね！
(母)ジャンヌさん➡
Jeanne.
Take good care of Nina for me.
ニーナをよろしく｡
はい｡
I will.
行ってくるね～！
I'm off, then!
-Nina! Bye!
-Be careful!
(子供たち)ニーナ ニーナ！
(子供)気をつけて！
Make sure you protect Jeanne!
ジャンヌさんを
しっかり守るんだよ！
は～い！
Okay, I will!
Bye! Have a safe trip!
As horrible as you are
I can't help but love you
Even while I waited
That is all I felt
Ephemeral lovers, both flawed and missing pieces
We have finally become one
In this miniature garden at the edge of sorrow
Can you hear my heart speaking?
Ah, I may no longer feel
That I want to go back in time
But there are feelings I have that I only feel now
I want to escape with you Dancing
Just like a fairy tale
Don't tell me it will only be this once, Darling
I am on the same ark
Shararanla Shararanla
Yeah
Cinderella step
Shararanla Shararanla
Yeah
Cinderella step
あと どのくらいもつ？
How much longer will it hold?
We exceeded the limits long ago.
限界は とうに過ぎています｡
Jeanne!
What can you cook best?
- Why all of a sudden? Cook best?
- Uh ye- yes!
Next time on Rage of Bahamut:
Virgin Soul, "City of the Gods: Part 1"
- Cook best...?
- What? What's wrong?
- Soup made into stew!
- That's just soup!
BAHA SOUL!!
Baha Baha Baha Soul!
I'm counting on you to watch next time.